rocket-internet.com 2019-11-13

# Imprint | Rocket Internet

###### Rocket Internet SE

[Charlottenstraße 4  
10969 Berlin  
Deutschland](https://www.google.de/maps/place/Charlottenstra%C3%9Fe+4,+10969+Berlin/@52.5067072,13.3912964,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x47a851d6a834a193:0xf66933bc4cb19e20!8m2!3d52.5067072!4d13.3934851 "Show me on Google Maps")  
F. +49 30 300 13 18-99  
F. +49 30 233 21 153 (Stimmrechtsmitteilungen)  
USt-IdNr.: DE256469659

Management Board: Oliver Samwer (CEO), Alexander Kudlich  
Chairman of the Supervisory Board: Prof. Dr. Marcus Englert  
Registration Court: Amtsgericht Charlottenburg, Registration No.: HRB 165662 B 

#### Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy contains information about our use of your personal data with regard to the website [www.rocket-internet.com](http://www.rocket-internet.com/) and your rights. You can save and print this privacy policy at any time.

###### Responsible Contact

The data controller (hereinafter referred to as “Rocket Internet” or “we”) in the sense of the GDPR and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection regulations is:

**Rocket Internet SE**

Charlottenstraße 4  
10969 Berlin  
Deutschland  
T. +49 30 300 13 18-00  
F. +49 30 300 13 18-99  

You can contact our data protection officer by mail at the address indicated above with the addition ‘Data Protection Officer’.

###### Collection and Use of Personal Data

We collect personal data if you voluntarily transfer them to us by contacting us, for example via a subscription form or email. We will only collect your personal data with your consent. The type of data that will be collected in the contact form can be seen on our website in the respective contact form. Data transmitted through the contact form will be stored on servers located in Germany. We use the data you provide to us to process your inquiries. Depending on the purpose we may collect and store title, name, company, job title, address, gender, date of birth, phone number, and email address. Unless specifically stated, we store personal data only as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes pursued.

###### Investor Relations subscription

If you register for our Investor Relations updates, we will use your email address to regularly inform you about Rocket Internet SE and its companies, including but not limited to the company newsletter, corporate news, investor relations related information and invitations to events of Rocket Internet and its companies. Mandatory for receiving these information are the following data: name, address, email address, job title and company. Further data can be added voluntarily such as title and phone number. 

To ensure that you are properly registered, that is, to prevent unauthorized subscriptions on behalf of third parties, we will use a double-opt-in process and send you a confirmation e-mail after your first Investor Relations subscription; this e-mail will request you to confirm the subscription. 

The registration is based on the following statement: “I would like to receive information about Rocket Internet and its companies, including but not limited to the company newsletter, corporate news, investor relations related information and invitations to events of Rocket Internet and its companies via email. To unsubscribe at any time I can use the cancellation link provided in each email.”

The legal basis for this is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 (1) sentence 1 a GDPR. In connection with your registration, we also store your IP address plus the date and time of registration and confirmation, so that we can trace and prove the registration at a later date. The legal basis for this storage is a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR, where the legitimate interest is in being able to prove the registration. We will store your email address for sending you the regular updates by email until you unsubscribe or we stop sending these updates to you. The data collected by us during the subscription will be used exclusively for promotional and informational purposes by means of the company updates.

You may object at any time via the cancellation link in the provided emails or by sending a message to our contact address indicated above without incurring any costs. After cancellation, your email address will be removed from our distribution list, as far as you have not expressly consented to a further use of your data or we reserve the right to further data usage, which is permitted by law and about which we inform you in this statement.

We use the reCAPTCHA service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, to safeguard the integrity of Investor Relations subscriptions. Through reCAPTCHA queries we can determine whether an entry in an online form has been made by a human person or an automated script. Your entry in the reCAPTCHA field will be sent to Google and processed by Google for this purpose. The reCAPTCHA application will also send your IP address and other data to Google to enable it to provide the reCAPTCHA service. By using reCAPTCHA, you give your consent for your text recognition entry to be used by Google for the digitization of books, newspapers, etc. Further information on reCAPTCHA as well as Google’s privacy policy is available **[here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)**. 

We use a service provider supporting us with administration and sending out the regular company updates by email. Personal data that is transferred when using the subscription form on our website will be processed by EQS Group AG, Karlstr. 47, 80333 Munich, Germany. Information regarding the handling of personal data by EQS Group AG is available  **[here](https://germany.eqs.com/en/legal)**.

###### Use of Cookies

In order to improve website performance, we use cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored on your device. Cookies remain on your device and allow us to recognize your browser on the next visit (persistent cookies). You can set your browser to inform you about the cookie setting and disable cookies individually, or to disable cookies for specific cases or in general. If the usage of cookies is not enabled, the functionality of our website may be restricted.

The legal basis for this processing of data is the improvement of the functionality and stability of the website (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR).

###### Use of Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Google Analytics uses methods that allow the analysis of the use of the website, e. g. through cookies. The generated information about your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. By activating the IP anonymization on this website, the IP address will be shortened before transmission within the Member States of the European Union or in other Contracting States of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the full IP address will be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. The anonymized IP address transmitted by your browser under Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. 

You can prevent Google's processing of the data (including your IP address) generated by a cookie and your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following **[link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.).**

Further information on data protection regarding Google Analytics is available at Google’s data protection notice under “Google Analytics Cookies” available under the following [**link**.](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)

Further information on Google’s privacy policy is available **[here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)**.

The cookie lifetime is up to 24 months (this applies only to cookies which have been set by this website) and the maximum storage period of used data is up to 26 months.

The legal basis for this processing of data is the improvement of the functionality, the security, and the usability of the website (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR).

###### Use of New Relic

The website uses a service by New Relic Inc., 188 Spear Street, Suite 1200 San Francisco, CA 94105, USA in order to measure and monitor the technical performance of the website and to collect application data for statistical purposes via New Relic. For details about the data usage in the context of the use of New Relic’s service, please refer to the data protection notice of New Relic [**here**.](https://newrelic.com/privacy) We do not collect, process or use personal data through New Relic. If you want to prevent us from analyzing your visit through New Relic, you can disable the use of cookies in your browser. The legal basis for this processing of data is the improvement of the functionality, the security, and the usability of the website (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR).

###### Website Security

We use and constantly improve technical and organizational security measures to protect the information provided to us and prevent personal data from being accidentally or intentionally altered, deleted, or accessed by unauthorized persons.

###### Rights of the data subject

If your personal data is processed, you are a data subject within the meaning of the GDPR and you have the following rights vis-à-vis the data controller:

###### Right of Access

Right to information according to Art. 15 GDPR: You have the right to obtain information about the personal data processed by us, the processing purposes, the categories of processed personal data, the recipients or categories of recipients to whom your data was or are being disclosed, the planned period of storage or the criteria for determining the duration of storage, the right of correction, deletion, limitation of processing, objection to processing, complaint to a supervisory authority, the origin of your data, if they were not collected by us, the existence of automated decision-making including profiling and possibly significant information on the logic applied and the scope and intended impact of such processing, as well as your right to be informed of what guarantees according to Art. 46 GDPR exist in case of redirection of data in third countries;

###### Right to Correction

Right to correction according to Art. 16 GDPR: You have the right to immediate correction of incorrect data concerning you and/or completion of incomplete data;

###### Right to Deletion

Right to deletion according to Art. 17 DSGVO: You have the right to demand the deletion of your personal data if the requirements of Art. 17 (1) GDPR are met. This right does not apply if the processing is necessary for the exercise of the right to freedom of expression and information, for the fulfillment of a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest or for the pursuit, exercise or defense of rights;

###### Right to Restriction of Processing

Right to restriction of processing according to Art. 18 GDPR: You have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data provided that the correctness of your data is verified, if you refuse to delete your data due to inadmissible data processing and instead restrict the processing of your data, if you need your data for the assertion, exercise, or defense of legal rights, after we no longer require these data for their purpose, or if you have objected for reasons of your particular situation, as long as it is not ascertained, whether our legitimate reasons prevail;

###### Information to Third Parties

Right to information in accordance to Art. 19 GDPR: If you exercise the right to correct, delete, or limit the processing towards the responsible contact, this person is obliged to inform all recipients who have been disclosed personal data about the correction, deletion, or limitation of processing of the data, unless this is impossible or requires a disproportionate effort. You have the right to be informed about the respective recipients;

###### Right to Data Portability

Right to data portability according to Art. 20 GDPR: You have the right to receive your personal data provided to us in a structured, common, and machine-readable format or to request transmission to another responsible person, insofar as this is technically feasible;

###### Right to Withdraw the Declaration of Consent under Data-Processing Law

Right to revoke granted consent according to Art. 7 (3) GDPR: You have the right to revoke consent provided in the processing of data at any time with effect for the future. In the case of revocation, we will delete the respective data immediately, as far as further processing cannot be legally justified for processing without consent. The revocation of consent does not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation;

###### Right to file a Complaint with a Supervisory Authority

Right to file a complaint according to Art. 77 GDPR: If you consider the processing of your personal data a violation of the GDPR, you have the right to file a complaint to a supervisory authority, in particular in the member state of your location, your place of work, or the place of alleged infringement.

###### Right to Objection

If you have given your consent (Art. 6 (1) a GDPR) to the processing of your data, you can withdraw your consent at any time. Such a withdrawal influences the permissibility of processing your personal data after you have provided it to us.

If we base the processing of your personal data on the weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR), you may object to the processing at any time. In the event of your justified objection, we will either stop or adjust data processing or point out to you our compelling reasons worthy of protection, on the basis of which we will continue (possibly limited) processing.

You can object to the processing of your personal data for purposes of advertising and data analysis at any time. You can inform us about your objection under the above-mentioned contact details.

###### Contact

If you want to contact us or ask us any question with regard to your personal data, please contact us directly via the details provided in the imprint or as indicated above.

Last update: 24 May 2018
